ma. fernanda rodríguez r.

MULTIMEDIA ENGINEER

Campinas - São Paulo, Brazil

🛮 🕻 (+55) 19 99612 2927 | 🔀 mafda13@gmail.com | 🏕 mafda.github.io/ | 🖫 mafda | 🛅 mafdarodriguezr

about me_

I have worked in different areas like **digital media** such as web design, digital image and video, and 3D modeling, rendering, and animation. However, lately, I have been immersed in the world of computer applications, mainly in areas such as **augmented reality** and **machine learning**, in addition to other areas such as computer graphics, computer vision, image processing, and interaction human-computer.

skills

Code My main development language is Python, but I have worked with HTML/CSS, JavaScript, SQL and PHP.

Design I feel comfortable working on web design and 3D graphics from Photoshop, Gimp, and Jekyll to Maya and 3DS Max.

Tools Some of the tools with which I have already worked as Git, Latex, Vim, Keras, and notebooks.

education.

PhD student in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Campinas — SP, Brazil

UNIVERSITY OF CAMPINAS — UNICAMP

Since 2015

• Thesis: 'Occlusion treatment in objects tracking for augmented reality systems'. Advisor: Prof. José Mario De Martino, Ph.D.

MSc. in Mechanical Engineering

Campinas — SP, Brazil

UNIVERSITY OF CAMPINAS — UNICAMP

2012 — 2014

• Dissertation: 'Development of a hybrid localization system for autonomous navigation of ground vehicles in a simulated environment'. Advisor: Prof. Janito Vaqueiro Ferreira, Ph.D.

Multimedia Engineering

Bogotá, Colombia

Nueva Granada Military University — UMNG

2004 — 2009

• Thesis: 'Development of a virtual an object of learning for management training of animal models in research processes'.

Advisor: Prof. Germán Andrés Garnica.

courses & certifications _

AGILE METHODOLOGIES

2019	Gestão Ágil com SCRUM, Onli	e	Jdemy
------	-----------------------------	---	-------

MACHINE LEARNING

2019	Introduction to machine learning & deep learning in python, Online	Udemy
2019	Master computer vision opencv3 in python & machine learning, Online	Udemy
2018	Deep learning and computer vision A-Z: opencv, ssd & gans, Online	Udemy
2018	Zero to deep learning with python and keras, Online	Udemy
2018	Redes neurais artificiais em python, Online	Udemy

3DSTUDIO MAX

2010	Materials, hair, cloth & character rigging, Bogotá, Colombia	Autodesk
2010	Character modeling, Bogotá, Colombia	Autodesk
2010	Advertising animation, Bogotá, Colombia	Autodesk

experience

DCA — FEEC, University of Campinas

Campinas — SP, Brazill

Researcher

• Explore the performance and potential of markerless tracking in Vuforia Augmented Reality SDK.

• Design, development and maintenance of websites with HTML/CSS, JavaScript and PHP.

• Develop a demo on mobile devices, as an auxiliary guide of an underwater oil exploration device.

Parexton The Web Design co.

Freelance

01/2010 — 12/2014

01/2015 — 06/2015

- Web Designer
- Development of SEO strategies with Google Analytics.
- Corporate image design and brand with Photoshop.

languagues_____

		Listening	Reading	Speaking	Writing
Spanish	Mother tongue	Fluent	Fluent	Fluent	Fluent
Portuguese		Advanced	Advanced	Advanced	Advanced
English		Intermediate	Advanced	Basic	Intermediate

publications

- 2015 RUIZ, M. F. R., De Martino, J., Pelaquim, J. "Augmented reality applied for the inspection and pre-installation testing of underwater oil production device". IV Congreso Internacional de Multimedia. Bogotá Colombia.
- 2015 RUIZ, M. F. R., Ferreira, J. V., Miranda Neto, A., "Referenced Localization Method Based on the Recognition of Key Objects from a Digital Map". IV Congreso Internacional de Multimedia. Bogotá Colombia.
- **2014** RUIZ, M. F. R., Ferreira, J. V., "Navegação sem condutor, mas segura". In *Jornal da Unicamp*, page 11. Campinas SP, Brazil.
- 2014 RUIZ, M. F. R., "Desenvolvimento de um sistema de localização híbrido para navegação autônoma de veículos terrestres em ambiente simulado". Master's thesis, University of Campinas.